Ben M. Herbster Papers
Ben M. Herbster Papers
1961-1969
Herbster, Ben M., 1904-
0.5 linear ft.
Printed material, sermons, addresses, etc from the American Protestant clergyman and first president of the United Church of Christ.
2741976
Biographical History
Ben Mohr Herbster (1904-1984) was an American Protestant clergyman. A native of Ohio, he was active in social issues such as civil rights. In 1961 he was elected the first president of the United Church of Christ, a position he held for eight years. He died in New York on December 16, 1984.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Ben M. Herbster Papers consists of printed material, sermons, addresses and other material.
Arrangement of the Collection
All series are arranged chronologically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Church and clergy; Herbster, Ben M., 1904-; United Church of Christ -- Clergy.; Christian leadership.; Sermons.; Speeches (documents); Clergy.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Ben M. Herbster, 1970.
Inventory
- Printed material
  - Miscellaneous, 1967-1968 (Box 1)
- Writings
  - Addresses and speeches, 1961-1969; undated; 10 folders (Box 1)
  - Chatauqua sermons, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Synods
    - 4th General, 1963 (Box 1)
    - 5th General, 1965 (Box 1)
    - 6th General, 1967 (Box 1)
    - 7th General, 1969 (Box 1)